Sunil Manandhar

sunil@ibm.com | +1(757) 345-9788 | https://linkedin.com/in/sunil-manandhar | https://sunilmanandhar.com

RESEARCH

I am a Security and Privacy Research Scientist at IBM T.J. Watson Research Center. I received my Ph.D. from William & Mary. My research interests include IoT security, privacy, software security, and NLP. My recent research focuses primarily on automating compliance in an enterprise environment using Large Language Models and advanced NLP techniques. I completed my B.Sc. in Computer Science and Information Technology from St. Xavier's College, Nepal.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Computer Science, GPA 3.85 - **The College of William and Mary**, Williamsburg, VA Aug 2016 - Jul 2022

Advisor: Dr. Adwait Nadkarni

Relevant Coursework: Advanced System Security Engineering, Advanced Topics in System and Security, CyberSecurity Research Analysis, Computer & Network Security, Advanced Software Engineering, Ubiquitous and Mobile Computing, Analysis of Algorithms, Intro to Machine Learning

BS in Computer Science and IT, GPA: 79.5% - Tribhuvan University, Kathmandu, Nepal

Nov 2011 - Nov 2015

PUBLICATIONS

Sunil Manandhar, Kapil Singh, Adwait Nadkarni, "Towards Automated Regulation Analysis for Effective Privacy Compliance" in NDSS Symposium 2024, [To Appear]

Prianka Mandal, **Sunil Manandhar**, Kaushal Kafle, Kevin Moran, Denys Poshyvanyk, Adwait Nadkarni, "Helion: Enabling Natural Testing of Smart Homes" in ESEC/FSE 2023 Demonstrations, Accepted [PDF|Artifact|Demo]

X. Jin*, **Sunil Manandhar***, Kaushal Kafle, Z. Lin, and Adwait Nadkarni, "Understanding IoT Security from a Market-Scale Perspective," in Proceedings of the 29th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), Los Angeles, CA, USA, 2022. *Co-first Authors., *Accepted*. [PDF|Artifact]

Sunil Manandhar, Kaushal Kafle, B. Andow, K. Singh, and **Adwait Nadkarni**, "Smart Home Privacy Policies Demystified: A Study of Availability, Content, and Coverage" in *Proceedings of the 31st USENIX Security Symposium (USENIX)*, Boston, MA, USA, 2022. *Accepted*. [PDF | Artifact]

Kaushal Kafle, Kevin Moran, **Sunil Manandhar**, Adwait Nadkarni, and Denys Poshyvanyk. Security in Centralized Data Store-based Home Automation Platforms: A Systematic Analysis of Nest and Hue. *ACM Transactions on Cyber Physical Systems*, special issue on Security and Privacy for Connected CPS (TCPS) [PDF]

Sunil Manandhar, Kevin Moran, Kaushal Kafle, Ruhao Tang, Denys Poshyvanyk, and Adwait Nadkarni. Towards a Natural Perspective of Smart Homes for Practical Security and Safety Analyses. *To Appear in the Proceedings of the 41st IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (S&P)*, San Francisco, CA, USA, May 2020. [PDF|CODE]

Kaushal Kafle, Kevin Moran, **Sunil Manandhar**, Adwait Nadkarni, and Denys Poshyvanyk. A Study of Data Store-based Home Automation. *In Proceedings of the 9th ACM Conference on Data and Application Security and Privacy (CODASPY)*, Dallas, TX, USA, March 2019. *Best Paper Award*. [*Press Coverage*] [PDF]

Sigmund Albert Gorski III, Ben Andow, Adwait Nadkarni, **Sunil Manandhar**, William Enck, Eric Bodden, and Alexandre Bartel. ACMiner: Extraction and Analysis of Authorization Checks in Android's Middleware. *In Proceedings of the 9th ACM Conference on Data and Application Security and Privacy (CODASPY)*, Dallas, TX, USA, March 2019. [CVE-2019-9351, CVE-2019-9377, CVE-2019-9438] [PDF]

WORK EXPERIENCE

Resear	Policy/Compliance • Enabling	ty and Privacy, IBM Research Analysis g Automated Understanding of Policy Documents for Regu on of LLMs for Compliance Automations	August 2022- ulatory Compliance
COVI	Model statewide pr	r Innovative Technology Evacy policies for Smart Community Testbed (ongoing) Systematic Literature Review on privacy challenges in Sm Interaction with Testbed Technologist and State/County of	
Co-op	Privacy Compliance Created Trained	e Framework pipeline for NLP tasks to automate information extraction Named-Entity-Recognition (NER) Model to extract data of the Classification using BERT	
Resea	rch Intern, IBM Framework for Priv Worked		Jun 2020 - Sep 2020 ation flow in privacy policies
Lead (Managed lab websi	Lab student-run meetings and organized events to improve rese te and logistics [Website] s in research projects	Jan 2020 - Jul 2022 earch skills
Resear	Designed framewor Analyzed Privacy P Designed framewor	partment, William & Mary k for Regulation Analysis olicies to develop insights into data protection practices k for generating natural home automation scenarios to imp concept exploits for vulnerabilities in access control enfor	•
Teachi	ng Assistant, Willia Computational Prob	· · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · ·	Aug 2016 - May 2017
Techn		al Language Learning, China ne for kids to help with language learning.	Dec 2016 - Dec 2021
Mobil □		oondrop, San Francisco pplication and Updated the App with Material Design <u>http</u>	Jan 2016 - Aug 2016 s://tinyurl.com/y65eafd6
Softwa 	<u>SiteHawk</u> - Crawler	Technologies , Kathmandu, Nepal r, and Interface for WebsiteSite Deface Detection based Mobile App for Side-Kick Plus Device	Jan 2015 - Jan 2016

May 2014 - Dec 2014

Business Associate, **Axon System**, Kathmandu, Nepal

☐ MyFarm - Mobile Application

Driving License Mobile App https://tinyurl.com/s6rjgmo

AWARDS AND HONORS

	<u>International Student Achievement Award</u> - Reves Center, 2022		
	NSF CPS-Cyber-Physical Systems Grant		
	☐ Title: "Enabling Data-Driven Security and Safety Analyses for Cyber-Physical Systems"		
	PI: Adwait Nadkarni, Kevin Moran, Co-Pi: Denys Poshyvanyk, Contributor: Sunil Manandha		
	□ Award CNS-2132281, totaling \$799,839		
	COVA CCI Cyber Security Dissertation Fellowship		
	☐ Title: "Improving Privacy, Security, Safety in Emerging Platforms"		
	PI: Adwait Nadkarni, Graduate Fellowship: Sunil Manandhar		
	Award Grant: 759381, totaling \$25,000		
	The Commonwealth of Virginia Engineering & Science (COVES) Fellow, 2021		
	S. Laurie Sanderson Award for Excellence in Undergraduate Mentoring Award, 2021		
	Distinguished Reviewer - Shadow PC, IEEE S&P 2021		
	Best Paper Award at CODASPY, Dallas, TX, USA, March 2019		
	Received 3 CVEs and mentions on the Android Security Bulletin		
_ _	Winner of Imagine Cup Nepal 2014		
_	Winner of Skype Challenge in Imagine Cup 2014		
_	President of Computer Science and Information Technology Association of Nepal (2014)		
_	Microsoft Student Partner - St. Xavier's College (2014)		
_	The food to be detected to the first of the		
	PRESENTATIONS AND INVITED TALKS		
	Enabling Practical Evaluation of Privacy of Emerging Platforms		
	UTSA - Alvarez College of Business		
	Enabling Natural Testing of Smart Homes		
	□ ESEC/FSE 2023 Demonstrations		
	Understanding IoT Security from a Market-Scale Perspective		
	 29th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS) 		
	Smart Home Privacy Policies Demystified: A Study of Availability, Content, and Coverage		
	□ 31st IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy		
	Towards a Natural Perspective of Smart Homes for Practical Security and Safety Analyses"		
	□ 41st IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy		
	□ IBM Research		
	□ Journal Club, William & Mary		
	Outlier Detection in Large Scale Dataset		
	□ 17th Annual Graduate Research Symposium		
	PROFESSIONAL SERVICE		
	Reviewer for IEEE S&P'24		
	Reviewer for PoPETS'24		
	Reviewer for Wisec'24		
	Reviewer for PoPETS'23		
	Reviewer for ACM Wisec'21		
	Reviewer for ACM WiSec '21 Replicability Evaluation Committee		
	Reviewer for ACSAC Artifact Evaluation Committee		
	Shadow PC for IEEE S&P '21		
	Sub-reviewer for Conferences		
	□ USENIX Security Symposium (USENIX) '19, '21		
	□ USENIX Safethings 2021		
	□ ISOC Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS), '20,'22		
	The International Conference on Information Systems Security (ICISS), '19		
_	Student Technology Advisory Committee (Arts and Science Department - William & Mary) (20)		